Guide to the Wilbur Lucius Cross Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- SUBJECT FILES, 1876-1948; Series II; 6.5 linear feet (16 boxes)
  - Mark Twain Centennial, 1935 (Box 17, Folder 203-204)
  - Mark Twain Club, 1935-1946 (Box 17, Folder 205)
  - Mediation and Arbitration Board, 1935-1938 (Box 17, Folder 206)
  - Merit system and Democratic Convention, 1940 (Box 17, Folder 207)
  - Merritt Parkway, 1940 (Box 17, Folder 208)
  - Mount Union College, Alliance, Ohio: oration, 1927 (Box 17, Folder 209)
  - Natchaug High School, Willimantic, Connecticut, 1877-1939 (Box 17, Folder 210-211)
  - New Haven Advertising Club, 1942-1945 (Box 17, Folder 212)
  - New Haven State Teachers College: Address, 1939 (Box 17, Folder 213)
  - New York Public Library: talk, 1920 (Box 17, Folder 214)
  - Newspapers: notes on eighteenth century literature
    - Daily Courant, undated (Box 17, Folder 215)
    - Daily Gazetter, undated (Box 17, Folder 216)
    - Daily Journal, undated (Box 17, Folder 217)
    - Daily Post, undated (Box 17, Folder 218)
    - London Daily Advertiser, undated (Box 17, Folder 219)
    - London Evening Post, undated (Box 17, Folder 220)
    - Old England, undated (Box 17, Folder 221)
  - Old Guilford: review, 1939 (Box 18, Folder 222)
  - Outline of Biography from Plutarch to Strachey, 1925 (Box 18, Folder 223)
  - Panik, Father Stephan Joseph: Jubilee Day, 1940 (Box 18, Folder 224)
  - Parr, Thomas (the oldest man in the world), 1931 (Box 18, Folder 225)
  - Ph.D. dissertation: notes, undated (Box 18, Folder 226-228)
  - Photographs, 1887, 1917, 1932, 1937 undated (Box 18, Folder 229)
  - Pilgrim letters, 1946 (Box 18, Folder 230)
  - Porter, Joesph A., Prize, undated (Box 18, Folder 231)
  - Portrait bust, 1940-1943 (Box 18, Folder 232)
  - Portrait purchases, 1933-1938 (Box 18, Folder 233)
  - Poultry, 1876-1878 (Box 18, Folder 234-235)
  - Poultry dealer, 1876 (Box 18, Folder 236)
  - Psi Upsilon of Philadelphia, 1944 (Box 19, Folder 237)
  - Pulitzer Prize jury, 1947 (Box 19, Folder 238)
  - Radio interviews, 1939, 1940 (Box 19, Folder 239)
  - "Science and Literature," speech at Brown University, 1925, 1940 (Box 19, Folder 240)
  - Shady Side Academy, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania
    - General, 1889-1940 (Box 19, Folder 241)
    - Address on Chaucer, 1897 (Box 19, Folder 242)
  - Sheffield Scientific School, 1913-1947 (Box 19, Folder 243-244)
  - Sit-down strike, 1937 (Box 19, Folder 245-246)
  - Smith, Sarah, 1876-1939 (Box 19, Folder 247)
  - Snow, Susan, 1880-1936 (Box 19, Folder 248)
  - South Carolina, 1913 (Box 19, Folder 249)
  - Southbury Training School, 1940-1942 (Box 19, Folder 250)
  - Staples Academy, 1885-1940 (Box 19, Folder 251)
  - State budget, 1937-1940 (Box 19, Folder 252)
  - State tax revenue, 1939-1940 (Box 19, Folder 253)
  - Sterne, Laurence
    - General, 1929 (Box 19, Folder 254)
    - Clippings, 1906-1910 (Box 20, Folder 255)
  - Thanksgiving Day Proclamations, 1932-1947 (Box 20, Folder 256-260)
    See also: Folio
  - "Third Terms", 1941 (Box 20, Folder 261)
  - Union Party, 1938 (Box 20, Folder 262)
  - United States Senate, 1944-1946 (Box 20, Folder 263)
  - Veterans Home, 1940, undated (Box 20, Folder 264)
  - Vetos and other messages to the Connecticut General Assembly, 1931-1936 (Box 20, Folder 265)
    See also: box 24, folder 308
  - Washington, George, Bicentennial, 1932 (Box 20, Folder 266-267)
  - Well, H. G. History of the World, 1921 (Box 21, Folder 268)
  - Wharton, Edith, undated (Box 21, Folder 269)
  - White Memorial Foundation, 1940-1946 (Box 21, Folder 270)
    See also: box 26, folder 342
  - Willkie, Wendell L., 1940 (Box 21, Folder 271)
  - Yale Alumni Magazine, 1946-1948 (Box 21, Folder 272)
  - Yale Alumni University Fund, 1946-1947 (Box 21, Folder 273)
  - Yale Alumni Weekly, 1899-1915 (Box 21, Folder 274)
  - Yale College Class of 1885, 1910-1938 (Box 21, Folder 275-280)
  - Yale College Class of 1885, 1940-1948 (Box 22, Folder 281-283)
  - Yale Graduate Club, 1923-1939 (Box 22, Folder 284)
  - Yale Graduate School
    - General, 1916-1940 (Box 22, Folder 285-286)
    - Addresses and reviews, 1924-1926 (Box 22, Folder 287)
    - Circular, 1909 (Box 22, Folder 288)
    - Prints, undated (Box 22, Folder 289)
  - Yale graduate student, 1888, undated (Box 22, Folder 290)
  - Yale reminiscences, 1922, 1929 (Box 22, Folder 291)
  - Yale Review, 1920, 1939 (Box 22, Folder 292)
  - Yale University
    - Honorary degree for Helen MacAfee, 1944 (Box 22, Folder 293)
    - Institute of Human Relations, 1931 (Box 22, Folder 294)
    - Provostship, 1922-1930 (Box 22, Folder 295)
    - Research reports for president, undated (Box 22, Folder 296)
    - Retirement, 1930 (Box 22, Folder 297)
    - Miscellanea, 1909-1924 (Box 22, Folder 298)
  - Yankee Cook Book, 1939-1945 (Box 23, Folder 299)
  - Yeshiva College, 1938-1947 (Box 23, Folder 300-301)
    See also: box 6, folder 71
- ADDRESSES, 1919-1945; Series III; 1.25 linear feet (3 boxes)
  Material in this series is arranged in chronological order.
  - 1919-1934 (Box 24, Folder 302-320)
  - 1935-1938 (Box 25, Folder 321-336)
  - 1939-1945 (Box 26, Folder 337-345)
  - undated (Box 26, Folder 346-355)
    See also: box 8, folders 86-91 box 8, folder 95 box 9, folder 96 box 9, folder 100 box 10, folder 110 box 10, folder 116 box 10, folder 117 box 11, folder 120 box 11, folder 121 box 11, folder 124 box 12, folder 142 box 13, folder 145 box 13, folder 147 box 13, folder 156 box 13, folder 157 box 14, folder 172 box 15, folder, 175 box 15, folder, 178 box 15, folder 180 box 15, folder 181 box 16, folder 190 box 16, folder 192 box 16, folder 193-200 box 17, folder 208 box 17, folder 209 box 17, folder 210-212 box 18, folder 230 box 19, folder 239 box 19, folder 240 box 19, folder 242 box 19, folder 243 box 20, folder 256-260 box 20, folder 263 box 20, folder 265-267 box 22, folder 284 box 22, folder 285-287 box 22, folder 294 box 22, folder 295 box 22, folder 298 box 23, folder 300-301
- WRITINGS, 1886-1927; Series IV; 2.5 linear feet (6 boxes)
  This series is arranged in alphabetical order by title, topic, or record type.
  - Connecticut Yankee: An Autobiography, undated (Box 27, Folder 356-361)
  - Connecticut Yankee: An Autobiography, undated (Box 28, Folder 362-366)
  - English literature: research notebooks, 1886, 1887 (Box 28, Folder 367-368)
  - English literature: research notebooks, undated (Box 29, Folder 369-370)
  - English novel, undated (Box 29, Folder 371-378)
  - The History of Henry Fielding, [ca. 1911-1927] (Box 30, Folder 379-387)
  - The Life and Times of Laurence Sterne, undated (Box 31, Folder 388-390)
  - Scrapbook, 1895-1921 (Box 32, Folder 391)
    See also: box 12, folder 143 box 14, folder 166 box 14, folder 167 box 14, folder 170 box 15, folder 177 box 15, folder 183 box 17, folder 202 box 18, folder 231 box 21, folder 269 box 23, folder 299
- OVERSIZE
  - Thanksgiving Day Proclamations, 1933-1938 (Box 33)
- Additional Material, 1931-1948; Accession 1989-M-060; 1 linear feet (2 boxes)
  Addition inventory by Carol King 1989 August
  Received from: Sue Crockford-Peters, 1989 Feb 28
  - Appointment books, 1931-1936 (Box 1, Folder 1-5)
  - Appointment books, 1937-1944, 1946-1948 (Box 2, Folder 6-10)